Evans Kupour

FULL-STACK WFB DEVELOPER

Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Thinker and a Creative Full-Stack Developer with 3+ years of experience in Python, Django, Flask for Retail eCommerce, JavaScript, MERN, MEAN, etc. Received SPOT Award and Best Scrum Team while working at Euphoria Technologies Ltd.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, ¡Query, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Node.JS

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

September 2022 - Present

Food Palace – This is a dynamic web app that lists and shows a list of menu items for a restaurant. Shows the number of likes and users can give comments and feedback on a meal.

Built with: JavaScript | HTML5 | CSS3, Bootstrap

Portfolio Web App - This web application that users can use to showcase their skills and samples of their build projects

Built with: JavaScript | HTML5 | CSS3, Bootstrap

Todo App — This is an interactive and dynamic web app which allows users to pinned task they will want to achieve at certain time

Built with: JavaScript | HTML5 | CSS3, Bootstrap

MICROVERSE Remote August, 2022 - Present

Mentor (Volunteer)

- Mentoring junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposing improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Providing advice and technical tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE August, 2022 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developing skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

KWAME NKRUMAH UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

June, 2018 - November 2020

BSc, Computer Science